EGESIMBA PINTOS IFEANYI (MBBS, LAGOS)

Address: 5 Obadare Street, Akowonjo, Egbeda.

Phone number: 08084849155, 09135882325.

Email: egesimbap@gmail.com

PROFILE

I am a medical professional with sound knowledge of the basic sciences and clinical practice. I am a graduate of the College of Medicine, University of Lagos (CMUL/LUTH) and I am armed with skills in public speaking, presentation, information research and project management. I am well versed in the use of PowerPoint and other presentation tools. An effective communicator and listener. Works well both as an individual and in teams. I have participated in various health awareness programs varying from infectious diseases like Lassa fever and HIV/AIDS to non-communicable diseases like cardiovascular diseases and obesity and less known gynecological diseases like endometriosis and I have participated in various free health checks to the general public. I am highly interested in Surgery, Preventive Health and the use of Nutrition as a way of optimizing health.

CAREER OBJECTIVES

- *To gain working experience,
- *Enhance my skills in communicating with patients, making diagnosis, treatment plans and follow-up,
- *To provide a better hospital experience for both patient and health care practitioners alike,
- *To further my medical training to consultancy level.

KEY SKILLS

- *Commitment towards patient care and patient health education,
- *Eagerness to updating knowledge on both well practiced methods and new innovations in the field of Medicine and Surgery.
- *Skills at Counseling and Patient Centered Care which allows for effective communication of patient's fear and concerns in a friendly and confidential environment.
- *Dietary Counseling.
- *Proficiency in the use of Microsoft Office Tools and Internet based research tools.

EDUCATION QUALIFICATIONS

2020	Professional Diploma in Nutrition, Shaw Academy, Ireland.
2016	Bachelor of Medicine and Surgery, College of Medicine, University of Lagos.
2009	Secondary School Leaving Certificate, Maryland Comprehensive Secondary School.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Dec. 2017 - Dec. 2018: Internship position at Federal Medical Center, Owo, Ondo.

Dec. 2018 - Jan. 2019: Medical Officer at X-serve Children's Hospital, Surulere, Lagos.

Feb. 2019 - Mar.2019: Medical Officer at Providence Heights Secondary School, Fagba, Lagos.

Mar. 2019 - April 2019: Medical Officer at NYSC Camp Clinic, Taraba State.

Aug. 2019 - Aug. 2020: Medical Officer at Medical Reception Station, Sapper's Barracks, Ilese, Ogun.

Sept. 2020 - Oct. 2020: Medical Officer/ ICU Medical Officer at Devine's Hospital, Lagos.

Oct. 2020 till present date: Medical Officer at University of Medical Sciences Teaching Hospital, Ondo.

PERSONAL SKILLS

I am Polite, Punctual, Honest, Disciplined, Dedicated, Dependable, Friendly, Hardworking, a good Communicator and Listener and also able to work with a deadline.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Participant at Virtual Training of Security Stakeholders on Integrated Risk Communication for COVID-19 Response organized by NCDC, 2020.

Health Talk on Women's health at St. Stephen's Protestant Church (Military), Ilese, 2020 Health talks on Lassa Fever to Ilese Comprehensive Secondary School, Ilese, Ogun, 2020. Medical Volunteer for Afara Leadership Centre, Iroto LCDA, Ogun State, 2019.

Participant at Nigerian Medical Association, Lagos Chapter Annual General meeting, 2019.

Completion of Medical Internship at Federal Medical Center, Owo, Ondo State.

Participant at Lassa Fever Seminar for Infection Control, Owo, 2018.

Participant at World Respiratory Day Workshop on Asthma, 2017.

Bachelor of Medicine and Surgery, College of Medicine, University of Lagos, 2016.

2nd Medical/Scientific Conference, College of Medicine, University of Lagos, 2016.

Award for Best 600Level student in Nigerian Federation Catholic Students (NFCS), 2015.

Community immersion at Pakoto, Ogun State, 2015.

Awareness walk on Endometriosis with The New Dawn Foundation, 2015.

Health talk to primary school students at Mushin LGA, 2015.

Awareness Walk and Health education on World AIDS Day with the Association of Medical

Students, University of Lagos (AMSUL).

Basic Clinical skills, 2014.

Head of Day 2 for Planning Committee of Nigerian Federation of Catholic Students

(NFCS) Week, 2014.

Committee Member, Planning Committee of Nigerian Federation of Catholic Students

(NFCS) Week, 2013.

Awareness walks on Cardiovascular disease, Obesity, Diabetes with the Association of Medical Students University of Lagos (AMSUL), 2013.

Basic Therapeutic Skills, 2012.

PROJECT

Knowledge, Attitude and Practice of Healthy Eating and Physical Activity in Students of the Main Campus of the University of Lagos, Nigeria.

LANGUAGES SPOKEN

English: Full professional proficiency.

Spanish: Elementary proficiency.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Basic Medical Sciences, Clinical Sciences and Public Health, Counseling and Basic Life Support, Leadership skills, Information Technology, Nutrition counseling.

HOBBIES

Reading, Listening to Music, Solving Puzzles, Drawing, Playing Video games, Coding

REFERENCES

Available on request

PERSONAL DETAILS

Nationality: Nigerian.

Sex: Female.

Date of birth: 01 Jan.

Marital Status: Single.